A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Developing Countries Program, Asia Programs, Office Files of Eva Wollenberg FA519
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Developing Countries Program, Asia Programs, Office Files of Eva Wollenberg
1991-1994
Rockefeller Archive Center
Wollenberg, Eva
Ford Foundation
FA519
1.31 Cubic Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
Alphabetical
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Biographical / Historical
Eva "Lini" Wollenberg is a natural resource management specialist who worked for several years at the Ford Foundation. Wollenberg joined the Foundation in 1991 as an Assistant Program Officer for the Foundation's Asia Programs. In 1993, she was promoted to Program Officer. Together with Mary Hobley, she wrote a program review of the Ford Foundation's support for community forestry in Asia in 1994, titled "Experiences and Advances in the Development of Community Forestry Programming: A Review of Ford Foundation Supported Community Forestry Programs in Asia."
After leaving the Ford Foundation in 1994, Wollenberg became the Principal Scientist at the Center for International Forestry Research (CIFOR). She then joined the University of Vermont in 2007 as the Director of the Center for Sustainable Agriculture. Later, she became a Research Professor at the Gund Institute for Environment and the Rubenstein School of Environment and Natural Resources. She also became the Flagship Leader for Low Emissions Development for Climate Change, Agriculture and Food Security (CCAFS).
Wollenberg earned a B.S. in conservation/resource studies, a M.S. in wildland resource science, and a Ph.D. in wildland resource science from the University of California, Berkeley.
Scope and Contents
Primarily documents conferences, workshops, seminars and other program related files.
- Asia Prep Meetings/National Activities, 1992-1993 (Box 1 (41000))
- Common Property Conference, 1992 (Box 1 (41000))
- Community Forestry Workshop -- Agenda, 1993 February 2-5 (Box 1 (41000))
- Community Forestry Workshop -- Vdaipur Notes, 1993 February 2-5 (Box 1 (41000))
- Community Forestry Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 1 (41000))
- Country Reports Comments, 1992 December (Box 1 (41000))
- Evaluations, 1993 (Box 1 (41000))
- LawAsia, 1992 (Box 1 (41000))
- Leadership Workshop, 1992 (Box 1 (41000))
- Program Notes, 1992-1993 (Box 1 (41000))
- Regional Grant Responses, 1993 (Box 1 (41000))
- Social Forestry -- Review -- Cecelia, 1992 (Box 1 (41000))
- Social Forestry -- Grant Tables, 1992 (Box 1 (41000))
- Social Forestry -- Memoranda, Faxes, Correspondence, etc., 1991-1993 (Box 1 (41000))
- Social Forestry -- Report Draft (Box 1 (41000))
- Social Forestry -- Other Donors, 1992 (Box 1 (41000))
- Winrock Farm and Tree Association (NFTA Spinoff), 1993 (Box 1 (41000))